import 'package:exo_planets/features/quiz/data/models/questions/questions.dart';

import '../models/questions/question.dart';

Map<String, dynamic> proximaBQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How far is Proxima b from Earth?",
      "options": [
        "1 light-year",
        "2 light-years",
        "4 light-years",
        "6 light-years"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "4 light-years"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of star does Proxima b orbit?",
      "options": ["Yellow dwarf", "Red dwarf", "Blue giant", "White dwarf"],
      "correct_answer": "Red dwarf"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long does Proxima b take to orbit its star?",
      "options": ["365 days", "100 days", "30 days", "11 days"],
      "correct_answer": "11 days"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Proxima b’s mass compared to Earth?",
      "options": ["2 times", "1.3 times", "0.5 times", "5 times"],
      "correct_answer": "1.3 times"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which zone is Proxima b located in?",
      "options": ["Hot zone", "Frozen zone", "Habitable zone", "None"],
      "correct_answer": "Habitable zone"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main challenge for Proxima b’s habitability?",
      "options": [
        "Distance from Earth",
        "Loss of atmosphere",
        "High temperature",
        "Lack of water"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Loss of atmosphere"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which telescope is used to study Proxima b?",
      "options": ["Hubble", "Spitzer", "James Webb", "None"],
      "correct_answer": "None"
    },
    {
      "question": "What factor increases Proxima b’s atmospheric loss?",
      "options": [
        "Lack of volcanoes",
        "Radiation from its star",
        "Extreme cold",
        "No water"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Radiation from its star"
    }
  ]
};
Map<String, dynamic> wasp12bQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How long does WASP-12b take to orbit its star?",
      "options": ["1 day", "10 days", "30 days", "365 days"],
      "correct_answer": "1 day"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the shape of WASP-12b?",
      "options": ["Spherical", "Egg-shaped", "Disk-shaped", "Cubic"],
      "correct_answer": "Egg-shaped"
    },
    {
      "question": "How far is WASP-12b from Earth?",
      "options": [
        "500 light-years",
        "800 light-years",
        "1000 light-years",
        "1200 light-years"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "1200 light-years"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is WASP-12b’s fate?",
      "options": [
        "Freezing over",
        "Colliding with another planet",
        "Being consumed by its star",
        "Forming a ring system"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Being consumed by its star"
    },
    {
      "question": "What method was used to discover WASP-12b?",
      "options": [
        "Transit method",
        "Radial velocity",
        "Gravitational lensing",
        "Direct imaging"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Transit method"
    },
    {
      "question": "How much larger is WASP-12b than Jupiter?",
      "options": ["1.2 times", "1.4 times", "1.8 times", "2 times"],
      "correct_answer": "1.8 times"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the surface temperature of WASP-12b?",
      "options": ["1000°C", "2000°C", "3000°C", "4000°F"],
      "correct_answer": "4000°F"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which constellation is WASP-12b located?",
      "options": ["Orion", "Auriga", "Lyra", "Pegasus"],
      "correct_answer": "Auriga"
    }
  ]
};

Map<String, dynamic> cancrieQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What type of planet is 55 Cancri e?",
      "options": ["Gas giant", "Super-Earth", "Ice giant", "Dwarf planet"],
      "correct_answer": "Super-Earth"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long does 55 Cancri e take to orbit its star?",
      "options": ["1 day", "0.7 days", "5 days", "10 days"],
      "correct_answer": "0.7 days"
    },
    {
      "question":
          "How many times closer is 55 Cancri e to its star compared to Earth?",
      "options": ["10 times", "20 times", "50 times", "65 times"],
      "correct_answer": "65 times"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the surface of 55 Cancri e made of?",
      "options": ["Ice", "Water", "Lava", "Clouds"],
      "correct_answer": "Lava"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is unique about the nightside of 55 Cancri e?",
      "options": [
        "Sparkling clouds",
        "Thick atmosphere",
        "Snowfall",
        "Ice mountains"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Sparkling clouds"
    },
    {
      "question": "What star does 55 Cancri e orbit?",
      "options": ["Proxima Centauri", "Kepler-22", "Copernicus", "TRAPPIST-1"],
      "correct_answer": "Copernicus"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was 55 Cancri e discovered?",
      "options": ["2000", "2004", "2010", "2015"],
      "correct_answer": "2004"
    },
    {
      "question": "How far is 55 Cancri e from Earth?",
      "options": [
        "20 light-years",
        "30 light-years",
        "41 light-years",
        "60 light-years"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "41 light-years"
    }
  ]
};

Map<String, dynamic> kepler22bQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is Kepler-22b’s size compared to Earth?",
      "options": ["1.5 times", "2.4 times", "3 times", "Same size"],
      "correct_answer": "2.4 times"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is significant about Kepler-22b’s orbit?",
      "options": [
        "It’s in the habitable zone",
        "It’s extremely close to its star",
        "It has a highly elliptical orbit",
        "It’s the furthest planet from its star"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "It’s in the habitable zone"
    },
    {
      "question": "How far is Kepler-22b from Earth?",
      "options": [
        "400 light-years",
        "500 light-years",
        "600 light-years",
        "1000 light-years"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "600 light-years"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is unknown about Kepler-22b?",
      "options": [
        "Its distance from the star",
        "Its size",
        "Its surface composition",
        "Its orbital period"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Its surface composition"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of planet is Kepler-22b?",
      "options": ["Ice giant", "Super-Earth", "Gas giant", "Dwarf planet"],
      "correct_answer": "Super-Earth"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Kepler-22b’s star similar to?",
      "options": [
        "Proxima Centauri",
        "Our Sun",
        "Red dwarf stars",
        "White dwarfs"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Our Sun"
    },
    {
      "question": "What year was Kepler-22b discovered?",
      "options": ["2009", "2011", "2015", "2020"],
      "correct_answer": "2011"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which telescope discovered Kepler-22b?",
      "options": ["Hubble", "Spitzer", "Kepler", "James Webb"],
      "correct_answer": "Kepler"
    }
  ]
};

Map<String, dynamic> erisQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How long is a day on Eris?",
      "options": ["10 hours", "20 hours", "25.9 hours", "30 hours"],
      "correct_answer": "25.9 hours"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long is a year on Eris?",
      "options": [
        "200 Earth years",
        "300 Earth years",
        "500 Earth years",
        "557 Earth years"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "557 Earth years"
    },
    {
      "question": "How big is Eris compared to Earth's Moon?",
      "options": [
        "Slightly smaller",
        "Same size",
        "Slightly bigger",
        "Twice the size"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Slightly smaller"
    },
    {
      "question": "How far is Eris from the Sun?",
      "options": [
        "3 billion miles",
        "6.3 billion miles",
        "10 billion miles",
        "15 billion miles"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "6.3 billion miles"
    },
    {
      "question": "What moon orbits Eris?",
      "options": ["Charon", "Dysnomia", "Triton", "Ganymede"],
      "correct_answer": "Dysnomia"
    },
    {
      "question":
          "What happens to Eris’ atmosphere when it moves far from the Sun?",
      "options": [
        "It thickens",
        "It freezes and falls as snow",
        "It evaporates",
        "It forms clouds"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "It freezes and falls as snow"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Eris discovered?",
      "options": ["1995", "2000", "2005", "2010"],
      "correct_answer": "2005"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role did Eris play in astronomy?",
      "options": [
        "It helped reclassify Pluto as a dwarf planet",
        "It was the first exoplanet discovered",
        "It has the most moons of any dwarf planet",
        "It is the brightest object in the Kuiper Belt"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "It helped reclassify Pluto as a dwarf planet"
    }
  ]
};

Map<String, dynamic> vestaQuestions = {
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is Vesta's size compared to California?",
      "options": [
        "Twice the size",
        "Same size",
        "Half the size",
        "Three times the size"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Twice the size"
    },
    {
      "question": "How long is a day on Vesta?",
      "options": ["6 hours", "12 hours", "24 hours", "48 hours"],
      "correct_answer": "12 hours"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered Vesta?",
      "options": [
        "Galileo Galilei",
        "Isaac Newton",
        "Heinrich Wilhelm Olbers",
        "Albert Einstein"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Heinrich Wilhelm Olbers"
    },
    {
      "question":
          "What percentage of the asteroid belt's mass does Vesta account for?",
      "options": ["5%", "9%", "15%", "20%"],
      "correct_answer": "9%"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of structure does Vesta have?",
      "options": [
        "Differentiated",
        "Undifferentiated",
        "Solid core",
        "Gaseous layers"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Differentiated"
    },
    {
      "question": "What space mission studied Vesta?",
      "options": ["Voyager", "Dawn", "Cassini", "Juno"],
      "correct_answer": "Dawn"
    },
    {
      "question": "What evidence of water was found on Vesta?",
      "options": [
        "Frozen lakes",
        "Water-related activity from impacts",
        "Subsurface oceans",
        "Water vapor clouds"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Water-related activity from impacts"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are Vesta’s large impact craters called?",
      "options": [
        "Olympus and Gale",
        "Rheasilvia and Veneneia",
        "Hellas and Elysium",
        "Valles and Meridiani"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Rheasilvia and Veneneia"
    }
  ]
};

List<Map<String, dynamic>> quizesList = [
  proximaBQuestions,
  wasp12bQuestions,
  cancrieQuestions,
  kepler22bQuestions,
  erisQuestions,
  vestaQuestions
];

List<Question> getQuestions(int index) {
  return Questions.fromJson(quizesList[index]).questions;
}
